So this is a very exciting day because
于是今天是个非常激动人心的日子，因为
we are officially starting the Gay to Lease journalism course.
我们正式开始了《盖伊·托·里斯》新闻学课程。
Traditionally, we've understood journalism and
传统上，我们把新闻学理解为
research as this method of just collecting information,
研究就是这种只收集信息的方法
organizing it, and then expressing it.
组织它，然后表达它。
But then along came a man named Gay to Lease, and he transformed journalism.
随后出现了一个叫盖伊·托·里斯的人，他改变了新闻学。
He transformed the way we understood research. So
他改变了我们对研究的理解。
we created something called literary journalism,
我们创造了一种叫作家新闻的东西
which is the idea
这就是想法
that journalism can be by itself be literature.
新闻本身就能成为文学。
The Gay to Lease method is going to teach us how to be creative, how to be imaginative,
盖伊·托·里斯方法将教会我们如何创造性、如何想象性
and how to engage with reality
以及如何与现实互动
and engage with people.
并与人互动。
We don't teach you this in school.
我们在学校里没有教你这个。
In fact, we teach you the opposite.
实际上，我们教你的是相反的。
We teach you the opposite. Don't explore. Just do what the teacher tells you to do.
我们教你的是相反的。别去探索，直接按老师说的去做。
Where did he learn this? Well, he learned this at home.
他是从哪里学到的？嗯，学的就是在家里。
The reason why is that
原因是因为……
his father was a tailor.
他的父亲是一名裁缝师。
His father was a tailor.
And he had a tailoring business in New Jersey.
他在新泽西有一家裁缝生意。
And his mother...
他的母亲……
took care of the business while his father made the clothes.
在父亲制作衣服时，他负责处理业务。
So what does this have to do with exploration and reflection?
那这跟探索与反思有什么关系呢？
Well, his mother was responsible for the business aspects.
好的，母亲负责店铺的业务。
So these very wealthy people would come to the shop
于是这些非常富裕的人会来店里。
and order very nice suits.
并订购非常好的西装。
And her job was to deal with them.
她的工作就是与他们打交道。
But it's actually very hard to deal with rich people.
但实际上与富人打交道非常难。
They can be very demanding.
它们可能非常苛刻。
So her strategy was to become their friend.
于是她的策略就是成为他们的朋友。
And how do you become someone's friend?
[32] 那么你怎么才能成为别人的朋友？
What do you do in order to become someone's friend?
[33] 你要做什么才能成为别人的朋友？
What must you do? Talk.
你要做什么？说话。
Wrong. Not talk.
错。不是说话。
The opposite. Listen.
相反。听着。
Okay? Do you understand? So...
好的？你明白吗？所以…
In the family living room, the mother would say,
在客厅里，妈妈会说，
I want to sit down on the
我想坐在……上
couch talking with these very wealthy people.
沙发上与这些非常富有的人交谈。
And she would talk just by listening.
她只靠倾听来交谈。
Okay? So her strategy for this is
好？她的做法是
that I am interested in you.
我对你有兴趣。
So that's how she became friends with all these very wealthy people,
于是她就和这些富有的人交朋友了。
even though she herself was not wealthy.
即使她自己不富有。
She had a mindset that
她有一种心态，
whoever came into her living room,
无论谁走进她的客厅，
whoever was a client,
谁是客户，
was first and foremost a friend.
先是朋友。
And she was interested in this person.
她对那个人很感兴趣。
She was interested in people.
她对人很感兴趣。
So she would spend hours and hours just listening to that
于是她会花上好几个小时，只是听那个人说说说。
person talk and talk and talk.
她会花上好几个小时，只是听那个人说说说。
And so you can say that this is exploration.
于是你可以说这是探索。
Curiosity. Okay?
好奇。
Exploration. But in the other room,
探索。可是在另一间房间，
the father would by himself sit
父亲会亲自坐在那儿。
and work on the clothes.
并且在衣服上工作。
Right? I'm not sure if you've seen Taylor's work.
对吧？我不确定你是否看过泰勒的作品。
They are very precise.
他们非常精准。
They are very exact.
他们非常准确。
They are very meticulous.
他们非常细致。
They're very disciplined.
他们非常有纪律。
They're very patient. So he could spend days
他们非常耐心。于是他可以在房间里花上几天时间专注于一件西装。
and days in his room just working on a piece of suit.
他可以在房间里花上几天时间专注于一件西装。
Right? This is the idea of reflection.
对吧？这就是反思的概念。
The pursuit of perfection.
追求完美。
So exploration is the pursuit of curiosity.
探索是好奇心的追求。
And reflection is the pursuit of perfection.
反思是完美的追求。
This is a Gay Talese research method.
这是一种《Gay Talese》研究方法。
This is what I'll be teaching you.
这就是我要教给你的内容。
This is something that will not just help you become a better writer,
这不仅能让你写作更好，也会让你更具创意、更有效的研究者。
but someone who will be much more creative and a much more effective researcher.
这将使你成为更好的作家，并且更具创意、更有效的研究者。
So even if you are going to the sciences,
所以即使你去科学领域，我保证你在这门课学到的技能无论去哪里都能派上用场。
I guarantee you that the skills you'll be learning in this class will help you wherever you go.
我保证你在这门课学到的技能无论去哪里都能派上用场。
I want you to go around Beijing and take pictures.
我想让你在北京四处走走，拍下照片。
Again, the idea is contrast.
再次，核心是对比。
Remember that here he says, New York is a city of things unnoticed.
记住这里他说：纽约是一座不被注意到的事物之城。
New York is a city of contrast.
纽约是一座对比之城。
I want you to do the same thing for Beijing.
我想让你在北京也做同样的事。
Take your camera and take pictures of contrast.
拿起相机，拍下对比的画面。
Things that other people would not notice.
别人不注意到的事物。
Okay? And take pictures of things that are contrast of each other.
好的？再拍下互相对比的事物。